A Guide to the Mordecai B. Sweeney Papers, 1830-1884
John D. Rockefeller, Jr. Library, Colonial Williamsburg Foundation
John D. Rockefeller, Jr. Library, Colonial Williamsburg
Mordecai B. Sweeney Papers, 1830-1884.
John D. Rockefeller, Jr. Library, Colonial Williamsburg Foundation
MS 31.22
1 vol. (212 p.) and 55 items.
Mordecai B. Sweeney.
Administrative Information
Access
There are no restrictions.
Acquisition Information
Gift, 1931.
Alternative Form
Also available on microfilm M-1553.
Biographical/Historical Information
Mordecai B. Sweeney, tailor in Williamsburg, Va., ante 1830-1833, and Methodist minister in Richmond, Va., about 1837-1846 and 1855-1863, and in Baltimore, Md., ca. 1848-1852. According to a note in the papers, he moved to Austin, Tex., in May 1871.
Scope and Content Information
Included in the papers is a ledger volume of accounts for Sweeney's tailoring business, which also contains the accounts of Sweeney and Vanderslice of Norfolk; also included are Sweeney's book of personal expenses; lists of marriages performed in Richmond and Baltimore; accounts 1838-1884; marriage licenses, 1837-1860 and 1881; and recipes and other miscellany. The names in the Williamsburg accounts include Burwell Bassett, Augustine Deneufville, Goodrich Durfey, [Dr.] Alexander Galt, John Maupin, Philip Moody, George Morrison, George Newton, Robert Saunders, James Scott, Richard Taliaferro, and Benjamin Waller. Tailor's accounts have own rough index.
Arrangement
Arrangement
Each series is arranged chronologically. Loose pages from the account book come at the end of the financial series.
Organization
The collection is divided into two series. The first series consists of financial papers. The second series consists of marriage licenses and certificates with a few miscellaneous items at the end.
Index Terms
Persons:
Bassett, Burwell, 1764-1841.; Deneufville, Jean Augustine, 1763-1838.; Durfey, Goodrich, d. ca. 1868.; Galt, Alexander Dickie, 1771-1841.; Maupin, John, d. 1852.; Moody, Philip.; Morrison, George, d. 1833.; Newton, George.; Saunders, Robert, 1761-1835.; Scott, James.; Taliaferro, Richard.; Waller, Benjamin, d. 1865.
Subjects:
Tailors--Virginia--Williamsburg.
Corporate Names:
Methodist Episcopal Church--Virginia--Richmond--Clergy.; Sweeney and Vanderslice (Firm).
Genre and Form Terms:
Ledgers (account books)--Virginia--19th century.; Marriage licenses--Maryland--Baltimore--19th century.; Marriage licenses--Texas--Austin--19th century.; Marriage licenses--Virginia--19th century.
Occupations:
Pastors.
Contents List
- Financial Papers, 1836-1884. (Folder 1-2.)
  - Receipt from McGrether to M.B. Sweeney, 5 January 1836. (Folder 1)
  - Receipt from McGrether to M.B. Sweeney, 4 April 1836. (Folder 1)
  - Bill, 18 October 1838. (Folder 1)
  - Bill, 7 December 1838. (Folder 1)
  - Receipted account of Mr. Sweeney with Haskins & Libby, 22 December 1838. (Folder 1)
  - Receipt. M.B. Sweeney to R.D. Brown, 28 July 1877. (Folder 1)
  - Memorandum, 14 May 1880., Printed document. (Folder 1)
  - Memorandum of cash paid, 10 December 1882. (Folder 1)
  - Memorandum, January 1883. (Folder 1)
  - Loose pages from an account book, 1864. (Folder 2)
  - Loose pages from an account book, September-December 1864., 5 pages. (Folder 2)
  - Loose pages from an account book, January 1878-December 1884. (Folder 2)
- Marriage Licenses, 1837-1881. (Folder 3-4.)
  - Marriage license, Henrico County, Frederick W. Maning and Catherine Ann Frensley, 20 December 1837., Printed form with manuscript insertions. (Folder 3)
  - Marriage license, Henrico County, William W. Howard and Sarah Ann Vaughan, 14 April 1838., PFWMI (Folder 3)
  - Marriage license, Henrico County, William J. Griffin and Mary Ann Norvell, 6 June 1838., PFWMI (Folder 3)
  - Marriage license, Henrico County, George B. Bohannah and Susan D. Perkins, 3 July 1838., PFWMI (Folder 3)
  - Marriage license, Henrico County, James A. Tucker and Mary E. Acre, 28 January 1839., PFWMI (Folder 3)
  - Marriage license, City of Richmond, George W. Raymond and Eliza A. Reeves, 4 October 1839., PFWMI (Box 3)
  - Marriage license, City of Richmond, Benjamin Boughan and Susan Stiff, 4 November 1839., PFWMI (Folder 3)
  - Marriage license, City of Richmond, John Blane and Charlotte Heatley, 7 November 1839., PFWMI (Folder 3)
  - Marriage license, City of Richmond, William N. Bumpass and Rosina Ann Fellows, 6 January 1840., PFWMI (Folder 3)
  - Marriage license, Baltimore, Brian Jefferson Conray and Sarah Ann Amos, 14 October 1848., PFWMI (Folder 3)
  - Marriage license, Baltimore, William A. Brett and Martha M. Rochester, 11 September 1849., PFWMI (Folder 3)
  - Marriage license, Baltimore, Daniel F. Keyworth and Anna M. Turpin, 5 June 1850., PFWMI (Folder 3)
  - Marriage license, Baltimore, Robert Jennings and Matilda Fowler, 6 March 1852., PFWMI (Folder 3)
  - Marriage license, City of Richmond, Alexander Drake and Martha Hicks, 17 April 1855., PWFMI (Folder 3)
  - Marriage license, City of Richmond, John R. Redford and Delia F. Sweeney, 14 April 1856., PFWMI (Box 3)
  - Marriage license, City of Richmond. Josephus Elliott and Sarah C. Morgan, 17 December 1856., PFWMI (Folder 3)
  - Marriage license, Henrico County, Alexander Hernaman and Christiana A.C. Newton, PFWMI (Folder 3)
  - Memorandum, 1858. (Folder 3)
  - Marriage license, Richmond, John C. Johnston and Ann S. Williams, 27 July 1858., PFWMI (Folder 3)
  - Marriage license, Henrico County, William E. Holloway and Virginia Gordon, 21 October 1858., PFWMI (Folder 3)
  - Marriage license, Henrico, John Thomas Walker and Susan A. Franklin, 30 November 1858., PFWMI (Folder 3)
  - Henrico, certificate for above marriage of John Thomas Walker and Susan A. Franklin, 27 December 1858., PFWMI (Folder 3)
  - Marriage license, Henrico, William B. Gordon and Frances H. Shepperson, 23 March 1859., PFWMI (Folder 3)
  - Certificate for above marriage of William B. Gordon and Frances H. Shepperson, 24 March 1859., PFWMI (Folder 3)
  - Certificate, John W. Padgett and Sophican, 1 November 1859., PFWMI (Folder 3)
  - Marriage license, Richmond, Robert F. Glasgow and Josephine Gordon, 20 December 1859., PFWMI (Folder 3)
  - Certificate for above marriage of Robert F. Glasgow and Josephine Gordon, 20 December 1859., PFWMI (Folder 3)
  - Marriage license, Henrico, William T. Ford and Emma J. Fletcher, 22 December 1859., PFWMI (Folder 3)
  - Marriage license, Lunenburg County, Richard Dyson and Catherine A. Sweeney, 23 January 1860., PFWMI (Folder 3)
  - Marriage license, Richmond, Andrew Atkinson and Susan M. Hicks, 19 March 1860., PFWMI (Folder 3)
  - Certificate for above marriage of Andrew Atkinson and Susan M. Hicks, 20 March 1860., PFWMI (Folder 3)
  - Marriage license, Henrico, William Barnett and Sarah Dyson, 9 April 1860., PFWMI (Folder 3)
  - Marriage license, Henrico, William F. Fletcher and Susan Warburton, 9 May 1860., PFWMI (Folder 3)
  - Marriage license, Henrico, Patrick P. Perrin and Pastoria Seaton, 9 October 1860., PFWMI (Folder 3)
  - Certificate for above marriage of Patrick P. Perrin and Pastoria Seaton, 10 October 1860., PFWMI (Folder 3)
  - Marriage license, Austin, Texas, Joseph Puller and Mrs. Eugene Dickens, 5 May 1881., PFWMI (Folder 3)
  - A drawing of Hagar & Ishmael, n.d., Frontispiece. (Folder 4)
  - Recipes, essays, etc., n.d., 5 pages. (Folder 4)